<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-02T02:14:33+01:00</updated><id>/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Lostarmour’s daily blog</title><subtitle>This helps him find his armour!</subtitle><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">What have I done?</title><link href="/what-have-i-done/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What have I done?" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/what-have-i-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="/what-have-i-done/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-was-i&quot;&gt;Where was I?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been blogging since 23rd October 2020. Now, I think this blog site will just remain active once in a while because now, writing every day is not possible. From October till December end, it was quite an exciting journey for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic is never-ending and that we have the new strain of coronavirus from the UK, all hell broke loose. In the Netherlands, there is a strict lock-down from December 15th, 2020 till January 19, 2021. I am writing this blog post on the new year day 1st January 2021. Although, the start date of a new year is a man-made convention to translate the cosmic phenomena of one full rotation time of the Earth around the Sun, with all the excitement, joy, hope, and beliefs of people about a brand new year make the same man-made convention so much more interesting. Having said that, I still remember when my mom woke me up on the new year’s day morning of 2000. That was already 21 years ago. I was 6 years, 6 months and 21 days old :stuck_out_tongue: .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone is reading this in the future, just know that I am writing this in an unusual excitement, so please do not mind my English :wink: . We used to live in asbestos roofed cozy and small house with a veranda outside. I wish I had a picture of that house. I remember her exact words. They were “Uthe, aji nua barsa. Dui hazar masiah heigala. Nua Shatabdi”. This is in my mother tongue Odia and it translates to “Get up, today is new year’s day. It is the year two thousand. A new century has begun.” I don’t know if she was really excited for that day or it was just a way to get me off bed early. On 2021 new year’s day, we video called with each other. She didn’t like my long hair though :stuck_out_tongue: .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schedule was pretty much the same as before. In the last two months, I did a literature review on some radar retrieval techniques for weather models. It was interesting as well as a little out of my comfort zone. I learned about dynamic estimation problems like Kalman and Particle filtering. Now, I am going more towards formulating the solution to my research questions of the Ph.D. work. I hope I will find a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schedule broke when I asked my supervisors for two weeks long leave before the new year. Although everyone is generally on leave on these days because of Christmas and New Year, I had also an added reason for taking holidays. I had been constantly working since February 2020 without a break. I finished my master thesis in August 2020 and immediately started the Ph.D. which was very tiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the holidays I had plans to visit the art museums of the Netherlands. However, with the announcement of the lock-down, all the museums were closed. Therefore, I stayed at home most of the time and got a little creative while cooking. I made some experiments and cooked some amazingly tasty food during the holidays. I even got some nice Christmas gifts from the department of the University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Chicken_satay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chicken Satay&quot; /&gt;
Chicken Satay with Peanut Sauce!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Puri_aloodum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Puri Aloodum&quot; /&gt;
Puri and Aloodum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Scrambled_Egg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scrambled Eggs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrambled Eggs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Murg_musallam.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Murg Musallam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murg Musallam!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Christmas_Dinner.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Christmas Dinner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmas Dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Mughlai_paratha.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mughlai Paratha&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mughlai Paratha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Charred_chicken_ramen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charrded Chicken Ramen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charrded chicken ramen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Muffins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muffins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muffins v1!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Muffins2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muffins2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muffins v2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Chicken_sausage_roll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chicken Sausage Roll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicken sausage rolls!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a mandatory ritual, I watched Home Alone 2, lost in New York on the Christmas Eve. :smile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/HomeAlone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home Alone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Alone 2, Lost in New York&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, I visited my uncle’s family for two days in The Hague as they moved here for a job for three years. It is good to have family nearby. I played with my little cousins. One is eleven and the other one is six years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Cousin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cousins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holidays got over with the blink of an eye. I also had some issues during this period and due to that, I was always busy fixing something or the other. On 26th December, there was a thunder storm in the Netherlands and the wind speed reached 100 [km/hr]. That night the operator spring of my window broke and for the same reason, the window had a full 180-degree rotational freedom, which is not nice. :worried: I tried fixing it but the window never closed fully. There was always a gap and the wind just found a way to swing the window to its maximum potential and bring it back to normal. I imagined the wind wearing a savage t-shirt where it says “Break, Swing, Repeat”  I tried sleeping in the same condition. However, the wind was too fast and the temperature outside was three degrees on the Celcius scale [with a “feels like temperature” of negative one due to the rain]. Thanks to my curtain, heater plate, and duvet, I slept peacefully at around five in the morning after all the struggle to fix the window. Even with all that temporary fix, I woke up several times with the sound of the collision of the windowpane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Broken_win1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Broken window 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Broken_win3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Broken window 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning when I was having my lunch downstairs, I heard a cracking noise and when I came up to my room, I found the outer layer of the glass broken due to the hard collision on one side. Then, I tied the handle of the swinging part of the window (don’t know how it is called) with a rope to the heater plate. This temporary fix worked like a charm. Now, I am waiting for the repair team to come and fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue that I had recently was a more annoying one. It was the smell of a dead mouse inside and outside of the room. I couldn’t find the source of the smell. While debugging the source, my nose experienced olfactory fatigue very easily. Finally, I found that it came from the highest shelf of my cupboard. I tried checking it, but I couldn’t find it. Suddenly, I smelled the ceiling and I got the most sensitive spot. Then, I confirmed that the thing that is dead is in the attic. That explains why I don’t hear the faint noises that I used to hear before from the attic. With all that information, I realized that I couldn’t do anything else. Going inside the attic is a hell of a task. I dropped that plan and I found that the smell is not that intense inside the room. I bought some scented candles from Lidl as they were there from the time of Christmas. I never knew that I would be needing them for this reason. Anyway, I bought six of those and lit up three by the side of my window. The candles are old I guess and that is the reason I don’t smell something out of them very strong. However, it kind of did the job with some added room fresheners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the holiday season, with all the neighboring decorations made by people, my room didn’t feel excluded after I lit up those candles. It looks beautiful in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Myroom1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My room&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Myroom2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the year 2020 was not all that bad. I graduated cum laude in the middle of the pandemic from the master’s program at TU Delft. A memorable event indeed. I received my Ph.D. offer as well in the middle of the pandemic. I am grateful to everyone who was a part of my journey directly or indirectly. I hope this pandemic ends soon and I wish everyone good health and mental stability this coming year. I look forward to working harder in the new year with some lifestyle changes (healthy :sweat_smile:). Hopefully, I will contribute something to the development of society in the coming year. Fingers crossed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-log-lostarmour-log-0110211&quot;&gt;New log (Lostarmour log 01.10.21.1)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please read some more papers per day to catch up with the pace of the Ph.D. work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please continue reading “The Road to Reality”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stopped playing among us. Yay!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop cooking more junk and heavy food and try to make a weekly meal schedule like Sheldon :sweat_smile: .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Where was I?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oct22-23</title><link href="/oct21-22/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oct22-23" /><published>2020-10-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct21-22</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct21-22/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule-22102020&quot;&gt;Schedule 22/10/2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On October 22, I had to go to the university to collect my friend’s degree certificate as he couldn’t come to collect it himself as he works at a different city now. I started my day early and went to the university at 8h00. There, I met some colleagues. Then, at 12h30 I went to collect the degree of my friend. The secretary there was super nice. The elderly lady is a fan of the Beatles. I am a huge fan myself. Coincidentally, I was wearing a Beatles t-shirt. We had a nice conversation for sometime. She was happy to know that I was going to be here for four more years for my PhD. She even came near my office after sometime. At the office, I tried to do some work (literature studies) and printed some of those papers. I always print when I am at the university because I prefer reading from a physical print out instead from a electronic version. At 13h00, I had a meeting with my daily supervisor about my PhD progress. He gave me some insights about Doppler Radars in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While coming back home, I grabbed a kapsalon and later I had it for dinner at home. Then, I watched “Boy meets world” and after a few episodes, I called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule-23102020&quot;&gt;Schedule 23/10/2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On October 23, first, unexpectedly I woke up at 4h00 which was super early. I woke up from a dream. I wanted to remember and write it. It was a super weird but really interesting dream. I was with my cousins on a rooftop. There were some people from a space agency who were showing us some objects in the sky. One of my cousins tried to hold a piece of glass and suddenly the sky looked really different. It looked like a curved piece of glass and the patterns on one side were moving to the other when he moved the piece of glass on his hand. It was like a remote control. Then, he tried to go to the edge of the roof hoping that he would see some new objects from one side of the sky. However, the people from the agency pointed out that the pattern will repeat and it won’t show anything new from what he had seen before. Then, an interesting thing happened. They got a signal on their system and when they debugged, they found that the signal has come from two thousand light years. It looked like a small lego-house and it had “Einstein” written on it. It was super weird, because if the house had taken off from Earth, the event must have happened at least two thousand years back (assuming that the house is traveling at maximum speed allowed.). It can be certainly more than two thousand years. And before two thousand years, there was no person as “Einstein”. This weird dream came to an end and I woke up. I guess based on some Freud theories, I think this is a consequence of the fact that in the recent TV series and movies that I have been watching, I am hearing the term “Einstein Rosen Bridge” a lot. And as a physics enthusiast, I know it is related to worm-holes. So, there is a possibility that this house has experienced something similar and now is at a different galaxy. I have my scribble at 4h00 is attached here in this blog-post. I slept again after writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dream_23102020.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Dream of 23/10/2020&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 10h00. I received an email from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aboutyou.nl&lt;/code&gt; that the package that I had ordered was arriving soon. I got the package at 14h00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/converse.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Order from aboutyou.nl&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was delivered to my neighbor. I had ordered a pair of all star Chuck Taylor red :heart: and one one Levi’s stay loose denim (Which is made out of a sustainable material). This thing is trendy and cool too. :wink: They both look amazing together. I got them with a discount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/denim.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Denim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I started preparing my talk for the seminar. I was about to present to my group at the university about how to use the group’s computing servers for MATLAB and for FEKO simulations. I had some problems in the beginning related to screen sharing online with Microsoft Teams, but I managed to offer a nice talk. It got over at 16h00 and the audience liked the overview. The session was recorded so that the new students/employees can look it up for references in future. I need to update the presentation and paste it inside the network drive of the group next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 18h00, I was already hungry. I went to lidl to bring some stuff. I brought some chicken drumsticks and I cooked my home style (odia style) chicken curry with mustard oil. Then, I watched some “Boy meets world” and called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-log-lostarmour-log-2310201&quot;&gt;New log (Lostarmour log 23.10.20.1)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please read some more papers per day to catch up the pace of the Ph.D. work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Thursday, I cleared things out with my daily supervisor about the expectation for my daily work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again started playing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;among us&lt;/code&gt;. Please stop it soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Schedule 22/10/2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oct19</title><link href="/oct19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oct19" /><published>2020-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct19</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct19/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I consider as a big day in my life. Although I graduated from my master program here at TU Delft on 27th August, my degree wasn’t awarded to me on that day due to corona-virus situation. This was the day, I had the appointment at the university to collect the degree. I collected it at 11h20. It was a very nice feeling indeed. The staff who handed it over to me congratulated me for my success and for the &lt;em&gt;cum laude&lt;/em&gt; that I received with my degree. I was super happy to see my blood, sweat and tears that printed in that one piece of paper. For sometime, I won’t lie, I felt like Sheldon Cooper :stuck_out_tongue: .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum laude ( Latin : cum = met, laus = honors, ‘with honors’) is a designation used when people with high marks pass their university or master’s degree exams. (source: wiki)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I went to my office at the university and studied till 15h30. Then, I came home walking. A weird and rare thing happened to me while I was walking inside the university campus. A girl was cycling towards me with absolutely no headphones on, yet, she was singing. It is a from a British band that I like. They are called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AltJ&lt;/code&gt; . The song is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Breezeblocks&lt;/code&gt;. I won’t say which part of the song she was singing. However, the coincidence was very weird and unexpected given the fact that the band is not very popular (I guess people are too stupid and ignorant these days to appreciate the beauty of such a genius band).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While coming back, I grabbed a pita chicken gyros from a Greek take away shop and came home. These days, I like walking to the university for two reasons. First, while walking, I get a lot of ideas and day dreams :satisfied: . Second, I have got a flat tire and I don’t want to fix it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made butter chicken with my house-mates for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-log-lostarmour-log-1910201&quot;&gt;New log (Lostarmour log 19.10.20.1)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start writing the presentation about the department servers. I need to do an introduction about how to use the RedHat Linux servers for different purposes along with how to debug the frequent problems that occur in them for the employees and also for the new master students in our group. Will be fun sharing my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Please read some papers to catch up the pace of the Ph.D. work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally you see some github flavored emojis in the page now :rocket:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Schedule</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oct20-21</title><link href="/oct2-21/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oct20-21" /><published>2020-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct2-21</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct2-21/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two days had similar schedule. I woke up early. I started doing the presentation about the servers for the group for half day. I started reading some papers on atmospheric remote sensing and turbulence modeling. I used another half day for that. Although, I started reading the papers, I didn’t utilize the entire half day on it. My legs were aching a lot. This is due to the fact that on Monday, I had to come down 21 floors in the faculty building due to a minor fire. Therefore, I slept in between while studying on the second half of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, in the evening I cooked dinner with my friend and watched the series “Boy meets world”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-log-lostarmour-log-2110201&quot;&gt;New log (Lostarmour log 21.10.20.1)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please read some more papers per day to catch up the pace of the Ph.D. work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have to clear some things out about my Ph.D. short term requirements with the daily supervisor on Thursday.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally stopped playing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;among us&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Schedule</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oct16-18</title><link href="/oct16-18/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oct16-18" /><published>2020-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct16-18</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct16-18/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a happy weekend. On Friday, I had a midterm to attend from a master student. It was about antennas and optimization. I really enjoyed it and also asked many questions. After work, I started a movie marathon on disney+. It was all from Marvel. I watched three movies. Had some nice dinner and slept very late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, woke up very late. I again started watching Marvel. I cooked some Coq-au-vin-blanc chicken but with some piri piri touch to it. It was delicious. Forgive my pathetic photography skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/coqauvin.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Coq-au-vin-blanc chicken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday also pretty much went the same way. I had to go to buy a cake in the afternoon for the birthday of one of my house-mates. The supermarket was crowded. We celebrated his birthday at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-log-lostarmour-log-1810201&quot;&gt;New log (Lostarmour log 18.10.20.1)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start writing the presentation about the department servers. I need to do an introduction about how to use the RedHat Linux servers for different purposes along with how to debug the frequent problems that occur in them for the employees and also for the new master students in our group. Will be fun sharing my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stop wasting so much time in weekends. Please read some papers to catch up the pace of the Ph.D. work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Schedule</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oct15</title><link href="/oct15/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oct15" /><published>2020-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct15</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct15/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-schedule&quot;&gt;The schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started the day late at almost 9h00 EST. I wanted to study and when I looked at the lecture slides of sensor signal and data processing (SSDP), I was a little lost. Therefore, I started looking for YouTube videos explaining the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a nice sandwich for brunch with homemade hot chocolate. I watched two episodes of “boy meets world”. Then, I started to study again. I stopped studying after the meeting with my supervisor. I was feeling a little exhausted. I attended the lecture of SSDP and pretty much didn’t understand anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had dinner at almost 20h00. We ordered pizzas from Dominos with a nice discount. While eating we watched one of my all time favorite; Home Alone 2, Lost in New York. I have probably watched it more than a 150 times. It was not enough TV for me. So, I watched Iron Man also after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-related&quot;&gt;Work related&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, got things on track as far as the scope of the project is concerned. I am going to study more about turbulence and the modeling of rain drop size distribution. Got some insight from my daily supervisor and also got to know that some other people have addressed some problems like this in the literature. Conventionally, drop size distribution (DSD) in a wind model is considered uniform. However, these people from Israel have done models which take into account these effects and they are rare. To use them, I need to study them first. Furthermore, I need to think how those data can be used for radar observations. I probably need to sample that data with the specifications of the radar. It is like looking at the model from time to time and not getting all the minute details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model, however will contain all the details with maximum sampling in space and time. Now, for uniform DSD and for non-uniform DSD, I need to study the models from the literature. That is what we have agreed on as my short term goals for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I need to find models where they consider evaporation into account. Sometimes, bigger rain drops, when they fall, on the way they evaporate and never make it to the ground. The model developed by people so far don’t consider that effect for precipitation. It can be a good research question for me for future. Therefore, DSD and evaporation at the time of precipitation are two of the open questions I have bumped into so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;note-to-self&quot;&gt;Note to self&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pending-or-on-going-from-yesterday-lostarmour-log-1510200&quot;&gt;Pending or on going from yesterday: (Lostarmour log 15.10.20.0)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be a little organized from tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to use GithHub flavored emojis on this blog so that I do not have to use :P, :D and or &amp;lt;3. When I figure it out, I will write about them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try reading the book “Doppler radar and Weather Observation”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try reading one page of the book “General Theory of Relativity” by Paul Dirac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-log-lostarmour-log-1510201&quot;&gt;New log (Lostarmour log 15.10.20.1)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write the diary earlier than today. Definitely earlier than 23h30 EST.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn about Large Eddy Simulations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start writing the presentation about the department servers. I need to do an introduction about how to use the RedHat Linux servers for different purposes along with how to debug the frequent problems that occur in them for the employees and also for the new master students in our group. Will be fun sharing my experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">The schedule</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oct14</title><link href="/oct13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oct14" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct13</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct13/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-schedule&quot;&gt;The schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I started my day a little late, around 9h30 EST. I wanted to study, but couldn’t concentrate well. However, I started a little bit and took intermittent breaks. Somehow, I managed to read two lectures of a course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I cooked lunch and had it together with my house-mates. We cooked egg biryani. I had some fried cubed potatoes with it as well. Although, people from west India believe that adding potatoes is weird, we, people from the east India believe that it is some sort of magic. Well, we don’t agree to each other to some extent, but, somehow I feel they are believing my theory. I mean, why not? At last, in fact, it is the truth. You add in potatoes and it becomes flavorful after taking all the goodness of the gravy. In fact, one of them is now putting chicken with potatoes in the oven. It is his favorite way of cooking chicken now. It is easy, fast and delicious. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I came back to study a little more, especially, some examples of the theory I had looked into. After two or three hours, I felt asleep spontaneously for one and a half hours. When I woke up, it was already 18h30 EST. I called mom and dad. A younger cousin was a bonus in that phone call. :P I had ordered Arsenic Album 30 (A homeopathic medicine which helps boost immunity in the body) from Germany. As my parents already know how to use it, I asked them how to. This medicine is necessary in these dark times. Although it is not a vaccine, it may help reduce the multiplication of the virus if it comes inside the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, at 19h30 I started cooking dinner with one friend. We, all house-mates had dinner and talked about machines and if they are going to overpower humans in the end. My conclusion was a “No” because I believe unsupervised learning may lead to over-estimation :P. We should either work on it or wait for the superpowers of the world to share a comparative studies. However, reading Asimov in our free time is also a very good idea. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I came to my room and had some Pepsi. Watched 2 episodes of “Boy meets world” on Disney+ . This is one show that I watched as a kid. It was one of my favorites. Although, I have taken Disney+ for the upcoming season of Mandalorian, I am enjoying all my favorite Disney shows along with the Marvel movies. I am surprised to find a lot of content in Disney+ . It has Marvel, Star Wars, Nat Geo, Pixar and also all Disney originals. What else do you need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-related&quot;&gt;Work related:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the study hours, I studied about linear and non-linear detection problems using hypothesis analysis. It takes me time as it involves more signal processing and I am from a fundamental Electromagnetic background. “Calculus” :: Yay!! , but “Matrix Calculus” :: Neh! Some people are out there who can relate to me :D. We are old school and we are the best. I feel good that I understand signal processing, and at the same time I think I will not be able to indulge myself in signal processing for a long time. I need to talk to my supervisors soon about the scope of my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I feel I should find more time to start writing the research paper based on my master thesis. I feel it can be submitted to MTT (Microwave Theory and Techniques) as my thesis was a very theoretical solver design. It is a theory developed in itself. However, I will also have to check Antennas and Propagation journal too. Winter is on its way and it doesn’t allow me to wake up before 8h00 EST. And, I have a time slot in the morning every working day from 8h00 to 9h00 EST to look up about the formats of these journals. Either I have to gather some energy to get out of my bed early or I have to shift this time slot to 17h00 EST. Most likely, I will stick to the former. Let’s wait and watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;note-to-self-lostarmour-log-1410201&quot;&gt;Note to self (Lostarmour log 14.10.20.1)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be a little organized from tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self appreciation by buying something from &lt;a href=&quot;http://large.nl&quot;&gt;large&lt;/a&gt; as they have some fun stuff with discounts (Some star wars goodies on the way) :P&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to use GithHub flavored emojis on this blog so that I do not have to use :P, :D and or &amp;lt;3. When I figure it out, I will write about them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop playing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;among us&lt;/code&gt;. It is addictive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try reading the book “Doppler radar and Weather Observation”. I got this book yesterday from the library.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try reading one page of the book “General Theory of Relativity” by Paul Dirac. He was an introvert. His book is also the same. Therefore, only one page. It is too deep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">The schedule</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction and “Why am I doing this?”</title><link href="/oct12/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction and “Why am I doing this?”" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/oct12</id><content type="html" xml:base="/oct12/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this day, I had this idea to blog my daily activities. I started my Ph.D. at the Delft University of Technology on 1st September, 2020. I thought it is a good idea to write the activities I do everyday on a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is built with jekyll ruby software (a static site engine, link in the footer). This involves a little bit of coding. This way I keep my hobby alive, i.e, designing, customizing and managing my own content online. I have been using ruby for a lot of things since 2013. I use github to host my website. This way, I don’t spend extra money on hosting. I write my posts with markdown scripts and push them to github after generating the static site using Jekyll. Pretty cool, eh? It also has the option to put math type-casting. Probably, I can use latex later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-am-i-doing-this&quot;&gt;Why am I doing this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our quotidian routine, with a job of any kind, we manage our time doing several tasks. Apart from that, we also manage to do personal activities like hobbies. We use online and offline tools to keep track of our activities all the time. Some people are smart enough just to use their brains and keep track of the activities without even having them noted down online or offline. There, brain acts as the tool. However, not everyone is a genius. We need tools to help us with that, especially when we do multi-tasking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of us use Calendars, Sticky Notes, Jira or even Trello to manage our tasks. My personal favorite is Trello. We can choose labels, check points and a lot of other options to keep track of our progress. And, to manage code versions, I use Github and possibly I will use the GitLab server of the department in near future. What could be better than Github?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything is already there, why am I doing this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer this, I should share my experience and observations that I had for the last ten months. I was a master student at the same university from August, 2018 to August, 2020. I was busy doing my master thesis from November, 2019 till August, 2020. I had several tasks to accomplish during that period. I used to write my thesis also while I was working. This saved me a lot of time. I managed my model codes on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, I was able to finish everything in time, I realized I had missed some of the ideas I accidentally formulated during this ten months. These ideas just came to my mind in different forms. For example, some came to me after I discussed something with my professor supervisor. In addition to that, sometimes I tried to gather ideas when I spoke with other people from completely different domains. Some even came to me just by observing the nature of daily subjects. Furthermore, as a connoisseur of dreams, I also like to remember and document what I dream everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up, I feel these thoughts need to be documented for future use. This not only will give a sense of self-satisfaction, but also will help in a lot of ways we don’t even know about. This is vital because your daily motivation can have a lot of information about your work, yourself and even about others. Fundamental physics teaches us that information is never lost. However, it also says that if we don’t have a way to define the information, it can change its form and to recollect the flying information, we may need a lot of energy and time. Therefore, defining and documenting the information is definitely a good idea to start with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tworit Dash</name><email>tworitdash@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry></feed>